good afternoon everyone so now we're
大家下午好，现在我们是
going to jump into the part of the
要跳进 的一部分
course that I'd call the real core of
当然， 我会打电话的真正核心
the course where we go into machine
我们进入机器的过程
level programming and by the term
高级编程 和术语
machine level programming I mean when
机器语言我的意思是，当
you're actually considering the the
你实际上考虑 的
individual instructions to get executed
个别指令得到执行
by the machine in response to your
通过响应 到 设备的
program and there's really two forms of
计划和有真正的两种形式
machine programs one is the actual
机器程序一个是实际
object code that runs on the computer
该计算机上运行的目标代码
and as we'll see that a series of bytes
正如我们将看到一系列字节
that encode instructions that the
该编码指令 的
processor executes but well because it's
处理器执行，但就是因为它
hard to look at byte and understand them
很难看 字节，并了解他们
there's various text forms to make it
有各种文字的形式，使之
more clear and one of those is assembly
更加清晰 的那些中的 一个 是组件
code that it used to be that tell people
代码，它曾经是告诉 人们
program machines and nowadays it's what
程序的机器和现在它是什么
the target of a compiler is is to
编译器的目标是
generate assembly code and I'll use
生成汇编代码，我将使用
those terms when I say machine code I
这些条款，当 我说的机器码我
sort of interchangeably mean object code
那种互换平均目标代码
the binary form or assembly code the
二进制形式或汇编代码的
text version of it interchangeably
它的文本版本互换
because there really is a one-to-one
因为真的有一个一对一
mapping between them but in case I sort
它们之间 但万一我排序 的映射
of used a term like assembly code when I
的使用像汇编代码的一个术语，当我
instead of consistently saying machine
而不是一直说机器
code it's because they're really the
代码是因为他们是真的
same general idea so this is sort of one
所以这同样的总体思路 是那种之一
place where this course 213 513 takes a
地方本课程213 513 需要
particular perspective that's very
特殊角度说的很
different from done ever elsewhere in
从曾经做过其他地方不同
the bad old days of computing you would
计算你的坏日子会
be required to take a course it was
需要采取一个当然是
typically called assembly level
通常被称为装配水平
programming the way you actually learned
编程你实际上 学习 的方式
to write programs in assembler and your
写在汇编程序和你的计划
assignments would be to do things like
分配将做的事情一样
to sort a array of numbers or set up
排序号码的阵列 或设置
some kind of linked list data structure
某种链表 数据结构 的
just sort of low-level programming that
只是有点低级编程即
nowadays you wouldn't even think of
现在你 就别想了
wanting to write an assembly code and so
想要写的汇编代码等
people didn't really enjoy those courses
人们并没有真正享受到这些课程
very well
很好
and so they got sort of our
所以他们得到了某种 我们
we cut out of the curriculum but what
我们削减了课程，但什么样的了
our version of it is is this is pretty
我们的是版本是，这是相当
important stuff to know as the sort of
重要的东西要知道作为排序的
gateway between what's how you write
之间有什么你如何写网关
your programs say and C or any other
你说的程序和C或任何 其他
language and how those programs actually
语言，以及 这些程序实际上
execute on a machine so machine code it
执行了机器让机器代码，它在
sort of the intermediate form there the
排序的中间形式的存在的
intermediate language and you need to
中间语言，你需要
understand that to understand better
了解到， 为了更好地了解
what your programs are trying to do and
你的程序正在试图做的，
what the machine is trying to do so as a
什么机器试图 为这样做
result of that our perspective will be
那 我们的观点会 结果
we won't actually write except in very
我们 实际上 不会 写除非在非常
very small amount we're not going to
我们不会对极少量
actually sit down and write assembly
实际上坐下来 编写汇编
programs in this course but what you'll
在这个过程中的程序，但你会
do is you're going to look at a lot of
做的是你会 看很多的
code that was generated by a C compiler
这是由C编译器生成的代码
GCC and try to see how does that what
GCC 和尝试看看如何做什么
came out of that compiler relate to what
出来的时候编译涉及到什么
went into it how does this low-level
走进它如何做这种低级
code implement the higher-level
代码实现更高 层次
of constructs that I was trying to
构建体， 我试图
express my program in how our procedures
在表达我的计划是如何 我们的程序
functions implemented in machine
在机器实现的功能
language how our data structures such as
语言是如何我们的数据结构，如
arrays and structs how are those
数组和结构如何是那些
implemented in machine code so we're
在机器代码实现的 ，所以我们是
going to learn all of that stuff and it
要学习 所有这些东西 ，它
takes a significant chunk of this course
借此课程的显著块
and a fair number of lectures to get
和 讲座的 相当 数量得到
through all that material because it's
通过所有的 材料，因为它是
really quite a bit but I think it's like
真的挺了一点，但我觉得 它 像
I said I think this is suitable core of
我说，我认为 这是 合适的核心
where this course is and as you know in
其中，这当然是和你知道的
this course we only look at one
这个过程中，我们只看到一个
particular classes of machines even
特别等级的机器，甚至
though there's many more different
虽然有很多不同的多
machine level programming possibilities
机器语言的可能性
out there and we've chosen the Intel the
在那里，我们选择了Intel的
64-bit version of the Intel instruction
英特尔指令 的 64位版本
set so I'll go through a little bit of
如此 设置， 我会去通过 一点点
the history behind Intel and how it got
仅次于英特尔的历史以及它是如何获得
to where it is we'll look at through
就在哪里 ，我们将 着眼于通过
this idea of how does C code relate to
这个想法如何 做的C代码涉及到
assembly code machine code and so forth
汇编代码的机器代码 等等
we'll go through certainly the low-level
我们将通过一定的低级别
basics that you need to understand the
你需要 了解的 基本知识
of what assembly cut machine code looks
什么装配切割机的代码如下
like and then we'll actually take on and
等，然后我们会真正采取和
look at some real code focusing
看看 聚焦 一些实际的代码
specifically on arithmetic operations so
特别是在算术运算等等
x86 is the sort of colloquial term for
86是那种对口语任期
Intel processors and the reason is that
英特尔处理器和原因是
the first one was called the 8086 and
第一个被称为 8086 和
then they kind of skipped 81 but then
然后他们那种跳过81，但 随后
they went to 80 to 86 and so forth 83 86
他们去了80〜86等83 86
so the one thing in common was 86 and so
所以在普通的一件事是86等
people just call it x86 and one thing
人们叫它x86和一件事
that's important to this and it will
这是重要的这一点，它会
have influence on what the programs look
有什么样的 程序看起来影响
like is x86 is a language like English
就像是x86的是像 英语 语言
that it's been an accrual and evolution
它一直以权责发生制和进化
of different features layered on top of
分层之上的不同特点
each other and not always the most
彼此并不总是 最
elegant way so just like English there's
优雅的方式 ， 所以就像 英语 有
all these sort of quirky things that how
所有这些类的古怪东西，怎么
you write it is very different from how
你写的是多么不同
you pronounce it and there's all these
你念它，并有所有这些
irregular cases and it doesn't make
不规则的情况下，它不会使
sense it's not sort of a
感觉它 不是排序的
purpose-designed language it's the same
专门设计的语言是相同的
with x86 it's a language that just got
使用x86它是刚刚得到一个语言
there because of a bunch of decisions
因为有一帮的决定
that locally were probably the right
在本地很可能是正确的
thing to do but globally were not
要做 的事情，但在全球范围并不
there's other instruction sets that are
还有其他指令集是
much cleaner and easier to understand
更清洁和更容易理解
but we figure it's just the same reason
但我们推测它只是 同样的原因
that you learn English instead of
你学习英语，而不是
learning Esperanto or something like
学习世界语 或类似的东西
that that it's a much more useful
这， 这是一个更为有用
language x86 is what sometimes was
语言是x86的东西有时是
called a Sisk there is a big thing in
称为西斯克有 一个很大的东西
the early 80s 80s in general called risk
一般所谓的风险在80年代初 80年代
versus Sisk Sisk
与 西斯克·西斯克
a well risk was a new relatively new
良好的风险是一个新的相对较新的
idea what they called a reduced
知道他们称为降低
instruction set computer and it was all
指令集计算机，它是所有
the rage and nobody had a name for what
愤怒和没人的名字 是什么
came before but the risk people named
来之前，但风险的人命名
what came before a Sisk for a complex
一个西斯克之前什么来为 复杂
instruction set computer with the
指令集计算机与
obvious
明显
a pejorative nature to that title and so
贬义性质，该标题 等
intelligent of the the classic Fisk
智能的经典的 菲斯克
architecture meaning it has a ton of
架构意味着它有一吨的
features we're not going to even scratch
我们不打算功能， 在划痕
the surface if you want it the the
表面上，如果你 想它 的
manual for it is two big fat books which
手册它是两个大胖子的书籍，
nowadays you do with PDF documents but
现在你 的PDF文档 做的 ，但
it's still a huge amount of stuff and
它仍然是一个巨大的东西量
some 500 or more instructions everything
约500页以上的说明一切
from doing decimal arithmetic to even
从做数字算术，甚至
decimal floating point and all kinds of
十进制浮点和各种
goofy stuff in there but it turns out
愚蠢的东西在里面，但事实证明
that you can kind of get a pretty good
你可以种得到一个不错的
handle on it by focusing more on just
处理它通过 更注重公正
what does the code look like that GCC is
什么是代码看起来就像 是GCC
generating for the kind of programs that
产生的那种程序，
you typically write and you should also
你 通常写，你也应该
realize that it many levels of this
认识到这许多的这个水平
should not have been the successful
不应该是成功的
design because as I said it just got
设计，因为正如我 说刚
lots of stuff on there but Intel has
很多东西在那里 ，但英特尔
been such a powerful company and had so
这样一个很棒的公司，有这么
much market and since better technology
很多市场，自此更好的技术
as far as semiconductors than its
至于半导体比其
competitors that's been able to kind of
竞争者一直能 种
keep this thing alive for almost 40
保持这个东西活 了将近 40
years this is pretty admirable so just
多年来，这 是非常令人钦佩所以才
to give you a suit of timescale as I
给你 的时间尺度 的西装 ，因为我
mentioned the 8086 was the first one of
提到的8086是中的第一个
the first single chip 16-bit
第一单芯片的16位
microprocessors it came out in 78 and a
微处理器是在78 和 出来
slight variation on it was a very basis
它 轻微变化 是一个 非常基础
for the original IBM PC which I know
对原IBM PC 我知道
predates most of you your lives but it
早你们中的大多数你们的生活 ，但它
was a sort of a the big breakthrough
是一种的大突破
that put computers on the desktops of
对桌面认沽电脑
many people and there's been many many
很多人有一直很多很多
generations I'm just giving you the
代我只是给你
highlights from that are relevant to
从亮点是有关
this particular class the 386 which
这个特定的类386，其
dates back to 1985 was the one that
早于1985年 是一个
really made the transition from these
真正从 这些 制造转型
being personal computers that could run
是个人电脑，可以运行
not very interesting at
不是很有趣的
locations - ones that could actually run
地点-那些能实际 运行
something like a UNIX or Linux machine
像UNIX或Linux计算机
and the reason is they extended it to 32
其原因是他们它扩展 到32
bits and they removed some of the weird
位 ，他们删除 了一些怪异的
addressing stuff that used to be in
解决的东西，曾经在
there so that these look like sort of a
有使这些看起来像那种的
generic processor and that was clear
通用处理器和明显
back in 85 and that was what sometimes
早在85，这也正是有时
called ia32 intel architecture 32 which
称为IA32英特尔架构32，其
was the dominant way of code up told
是的代码 了 占主导地位的方式 告诉
just even a few years ago so even up as
即使只是在几年前，所以 甚至达到如
recently as this past summer this course
最近在过去的这个夏天本课程
was teaching I a 32 and then there and
教我32， 然后有和
I'll talk about it more later there was
我会谈论 它 更晚一些 有
a reason in a strange story behind the
在后面的一个奇怪的故事的理由
extension from 32 to 64 bits which kind
延伸部从32到64位 哪种
of was sneaked in by Intel and an odd
都是由英特尔和 奇数悄悄在
model the Pentium 4 II but you see it
模拟奔腾4 II，但你看到它
was only about 10 years ago and one of
只有大约10 年前 的一个
the smart things they did would that is
他们做智能事情 会是
that the machines that can run the
该机器可以运行
64-bit code can also run 32-bit code so
64位代码还可以运行32位的代码，以便
they were able to sort of bring out all
他们能够有点 带出所有
these machines without everybody having
这些机器而不必每个人都
to change over their software and it's
改变了他们的软件，它的
taken about that amount of time for the
采取有关的那个时间量
software to largely transition away from
软件主要来自远离过渡
32-bit code to 64-bit code and then for
32位代码，以64位代码 ，然后
actually fairly interesting reasons you
实际上是相当有趣的考虑，您
could map how fast a single processor
可以映射如何快速的单一处理器
would run and it was climbing up at a
将运行并且将其在一个爬起来
pretty steady pace until around 2004 and
相当稳健的步伐，直到2004年左右，并
then Intel got and all the companies got
那么英特尔有和所有公司得到
into serious trouble with the power
与动力严重的麻烦
consumption of their chips they're
他们的筹码他们的消费
approaching 100 watt so imagine a 100
接近百瓦特所以想象一个100
watt light bulb and how much heat that
瓦灯泡和多少热量
generates inside of a box that you try
生成 您尝试 在盒子里面
to blow a fan on really hard to keep it
吹上真的很难风扇，以保持它
from getting too hot and they were
变得太热 ，他们是
reaching the point where they really
达到这种 地步他们 真的
couldn't go much beyond a hundred watts
不能去远远超出一个百瓦特
and so they sort of got
所以他们那种有
to a power budget problem and as a
功率预算问题，并为
result they haven't been able to scale
结果，他们一直没能规模
up the frequency how fast the inner
向上的频率有多快内
clock that drives this thing is beyond
驱动这件事钟超出
just a few gigahertz since 2004 so what
只是 自2004年以来 几千兆赫兹 等什么
happened was they said well we can't
发生的情况是，他们说好我们不能
make any single processor faster but we
做任何单一处理器速度更快，但我们
can put a bunch of processors on a
可以把一堆处理器上
single chip and those are referred to
单芯片和那些被 称作
cores or multi-core so most of you with
核或多核所以大部分的你
laptops probably have two cores on those
笔记本电脑可能会对 这 两个核心
and a laptop processor and a server
和一台笔记本电脑处理器和服务器
might have up to 16 cores so those are
最多可以有16个内核， 所以这些都是
independent processors that are all
独立的处理器是所有
reside on a single chip the shark
驻留在单个芯片上鲨
machines date back to 2008 and they are
机器可以追溯到2008年，他们是
each have four cores on them
每个有他们四个核
the shark machines the one thing about
鲨鱼机的一件事
computers haven't really gotten that
电脑还没有真正得到的是
much faster
快多了
of in the meantime so there's still
在此期间所以还是有
fairways and they were in their day a
球道和他们在他们的一天
very high performance machine so they're
非常高的性能机器 ，使他们
still pretty decent this shows a picture
还是相当不错的 这显示图片
of the chip that makes up a I think the
这构成了芯片的我觉得
the sharp machines or approximately that
尖锐的机器或大约 是
same era and you'll see that as the
同一个时代，你会看到 ，随着
picture shows these four cores are
图为这 四个核心是
integrated onto one chip and then down
集成到一个芯片上 ，然后向下
at the bottom is what they call a cache
底部就是他们所说的高速缓存
and we'll learn a lot about cache memory
我们会学到很多关于高速缓存存储器
but it's it's basically a temporary
但它是它基本上是一个暂时的
memory used to hold the most recently
内存用于保存最近
accessed data so that you can get to it
访问的数据，这样 就可以得到它
more quickly and you'll see that that
更快速 ，你会看到 那个
shared across the four cores so if you
在四个核心共享，所以如果你
look at the latest if you were to go off
看看最新的，如果你是走下车
shopping on in the catalog the latest
在目录中的最新逛街上
instance and I don't have any chip
例如，我没有任何芯片
pictures of it is a model they called a
它的照片是他们所谓的模型
Broadwell model and you'll see that on a
Broadwell微架构模型，你会看到一个
single chip they have multiple cores
单片机他们有多个内核
forfor a serious standard desktop model
forfor 严重 的标准桌面模式
eight for a server class machine and
八项服务器级的机器 和
then built around the perimeter
然后在周边建
there are various connections to the
有对各种连接
rest of the world so DDR is the way you
世界因此DDR的其余部分是你的方式
connect to the main memory what's called
连接到主存储器什么叫做
DRAM dynamic ram pci is the connection
DRAM动态RAM PCI是连接
to peripheral devices
到外围设备
SATA is a connection to different types
SATA是不同 类型 的连接
of discs and USB well you know it USB is
的光盘和USB那么你知道它是USB
and then the ethernet is the connection
然后将以太网是连接
also to a network connection so that's
也为网络连接 ，这样的
all integrated onto a single chip is not
全部集成在单个芯片上 不
just the processor itself but a lot of
只是处理器本身 ，而是很多
logic that glues that processor into a
该胶合该处理器成逻辑
larger system and one interesting thing
更大的系统 和一个有趣的 事情
you'll notice is that the desktop model
你会注意到的是，桌面模式
is a higher power
是一个更高的功率
65 watts versus the server is 45 watts
65瓦特相对于服务器是45瓦特
when you put a lot of computers in a
当你投入了大量的计算机在
room turns out power is the biggest
房间原来的功率是最大的
issue you have to deal with
发出你必须 处理
so intelligent the only company in this
所以智能唯一一家 在 此
game they're sort of historic competitor
游戏有几分历史的竞争对手
is a company called AMD and AMD was
一个名为AMD和AMD公司是
always sort of number two behind Intel
总是有点二号仅次于英特尔
in although I gave us his number two
在我虽然给了我们 他的二号
behind her but the they had a little
在她身后，但他们有一点
burst in time when they kind of got out
在突发时间时，他们种了 出来
ahead of Intel because Intel had wasted
英特尔领先的因为英特尔已经 浪费
their time on some bad ideas and they
他们的时间对一些不好的想法，他们
actually were the one that came up with
实际上是 说 想出 了 一个
the 64-bit extension to Intel that we
64位扩展到英特尔，我们
use right now though AMD is not just
现在使用AMD虽然不只是
doing very well
做得非常好
Intel sort of realized that it had to
英特尔之类的实现，它 必须
get its act together and it did and it
共同的行动，并且它没有和它
is more or less crushed AMD but and I
或多或少粉碎AMD，但 我
should mention that they had these
应该指出，他们有这些
ferocious patent suits many years ago
凶猛的专利诉讼在很多年前
and the result of that was across
并且 ， 其结果 是整个
licensing deal that allows AMD to
许可协议，允许AMD公司
produce x86 processors - now it's
生产x86处理器-现在是
interesting story behind Intel in 64
在64英特尔背后有趣的故事
bits they decided to make this radical
位，他们决定让这个激进
shift to an architecture that they
转移到一个架构， 它们
called the they called ia-64
叫他们称为IA-64
at the time and it was based on a whole
在当时，它是基于一个整体
new concept that looked really good on
新概念，看着真不错
paper and initial results looked
纸和初步结果看
promising
有希望
they invested a lot of money in this
他们投入了大量的资金在这
stuff they formed a joint operation with
东西，他们组成了一个联合操作 与
Hewlett Packard on this and it turned
惠普就这个问题和它打开
out not to work it was much too
出不 上班 是太
aggressive it assumed miraculous
激进它承担奇迹
optimization capabilities by the
通过优化功能
compiler and so it was a from a
编译器，因此它是一个从
technically idea it was very interesting
技术上的想法是非常有趣
technology but in the marketplace it
技术，但在 市场上它
didn't work and this was sort of a
没有工作，这是排序的
branch off that Intel pursued and felt
岔开， 英特尔追求和感觉
obligated to keep it up because they'd
有义务保持下去，因为他们会
invested so much in it and Along Came
它并沿投入这么多来到
AMD and they said well we don't have to
AMD和他们说好，我们 不必
do this radical shift we'll just sort of
这样做根本性的转变，我们只是有点
do the obvious thing of adding making
做制作加入的明显的事情
the registers bigger making things go
寄存器更大的决策事情
from 32 to 64 bits and they came along
从32 到64位 和他们来了
with that
与
and got a and were successful and so
并得到了与成功等
Intel kind of had to just sheepishly
英特尔那种不得不只是怯怯地
follow behind AMD on this but they could
跟在别人后面AMD在这一点，但他们能
because of their cross licensing deal so
因为他们的交叉授权协议，以便
nowadays as I mentioned hardware-wise
现在正如我所提到 的硬件明智
just about every processor that is in a
几乎所有的处理器 处于
laptop in a desktop even your cell
笔记本电脑在台式机甚至是你的
phones of recent generation are all
最近一代的手机都
64-bit processors so what we'll talk
64位处理器还等什么，我们将讨论
about then we used to teach ia32 but
关于那我们用来教IA32但
that's gone this is the first term where
该走了， 这 是第一项 ，其中
we're skipping it all together so we're
我们跳过它一起所以我们
using what we'll call x86 - 64 there's
使用的是什么，我们将调用86 - 64还有的
various ways this is named but this is
不同的方式，这是一个名为但这
sort of the Linux way of naming it if
排序的 ，如果它命名的 Linux的方法
you're interested in AI 32 there's a
你感兴趣的AI 32有一个
document on the web associated with the
与 相关联的网络上的文件
book called a web aside that goes
本书叫网页放在一边去
through at least some of the basics of
通过至少一些基础知识
it but to really read that you need to
它而是要真正 读懂你需要
learn the 64 bit because it assumes you
学习64位，因为它假定 你
kind of already know that okay so let's
样已经知道，好让我们
go in and I should mention - if just for
进去， 我要指出-如果只是为了
general interest the other major class
普遍关心的其他主要类
of processor in common use today are
目前普遍使用的处理器是
called arm so arm actually is an acronym
所谓的手臂所以实际上ARM是一个缩写
for acorn RISC machine I just told you
橡子RISC机器 ，我只是告诉 你
what risk means it means risk reduced
什么 风险意味着 它意味着风险 降低
instruction set computer an acorn means
指令集计算机橡实装置
like you know the seed of an oak tree it
像你知道一棵橡树的种子 它
was a British company
是一家英国公司
and that decide to make its own personal
并决定做出 自己的个人
computers in the early days of it and
在它 的早期计算机和
they said we're not going to buy those
他们说，我们不会买 那些
chips from Intel we're going to make
从英特尔的芯片，我们会作出
them ourselves so they designed and
他们自己 ，使他们 的设计和
manufactured their own chips well as a
制造自己的芯片以及一个
company a computer manufacturer it was a
公司计算机制造商，这是一个
complete bust but it turned out that
完整的半身像，但事实证明，
they'd come up with a fairly good
他们会拿出 一个相当不错的
instruction set that was sufficiently
指令集，这是足够
simple that it could be put on chips and
简单，它可以在芯片上放置和
better yet it could be customized so arm
更重要的是它 可以进行定制，以便手臂
is now a company of its own
现在是它自己的公司
headquartered in Cambridge England and
总部设在英格兰剑桥和
the reason why part of the reason
原因的原因的一部分
they're successful therefore is because
他们是成功的，因此是因为
it tends to be a lower power
它往往是低功率
requirements than an x86 machine because
比x86机器，因为要求
it's simpler but the other is that they
这是简单的，但其他的是， 他们
don't actually sell processors they sell
实际上不卖，他们卖的处理器
companies the rights the licensing
公司权利的许可
rights to use their designs and so if
使用权，他们的设计等，如果
you look at like a cellphone processor
你看像手机处理器
the actual ARM processor is a little
实际ARM处理器是一个小
tiny part of it on the chip and then
在芯片上，然后在它的小部分
they'll have other stuff to make the
他们将有其他的东西 ， 使
graphics go better to improve your phone
图形走的更好，以提高您的手机
calls and so forth and so they're really
调用等等，所以 他们真的 很
selling what intellectual property is
卖知识产权是什么
opposed to chips and so people we've
反对的芯片，所以我们已经人
gotten various inquiries when are you
得到各种查询 你什么 时候
going to start talking about arm in your
要开始 谈论 手臂 在你的
book or your course or something and we
书或你的 课程或东西 ，我们
go it would be another book to write to
去那将是另一本书来写
do justice to arm it would be like a
公平对待 武装它会像一个
whole redo of the thing and we were not
的东西全部重做，我们没有
inclined to do that right now
倾向于做 ，现在
but just so you know there's sort of a
但只是让你 知道有 排序的
two worlds out there x86 and arm are the
两个世界在那里的x86和ARM是
dominant players right now
现在统治力的球员
so let's talk some terminology and
所以让我们来谈谈一些术语和
you've probably heard some of these
你可能听说过其中的一些
terms before but let's make it clear so
条件之前，但我们要清楚这样
when we talk about the instructions the
当我们谈论 的说明
instruction set that's the the target of
指令集的的目标
a compiler to give you a series of
编译器给你一个系列
instructions that tell the Machine
告诉机器指令
exactly what to do but it turns out that
究竟要做什么，但事实证明，
the hardware people will figure out all
硬件的人会找出所有
kinds of clever ways to implement
种 实施 聪明的方法
instructions some of them are really
一些指令都是真的
fast but take a lot of hardware some are
速度快，但需要大量 的硬件部分 是
pretty slow but don't take much hardware
相当缓慢但不要花太多的硬件
at all and so they managed to create
在所有的，所以他们成功地创造
this this abstraction that's called the
这个这个抽象的名字叫
instruction set architecture which is
指令集架构，其是
what the target of a compiler should be
编译器的目标应该是什么
and then let the hardware people figure
然后让硬件的人的身影
out how best to implement it and then
如何最好地实现 它，然后
the low so that that's a concept
低，使 这是一个 概念
actually it came along in the 1960s so
实际上它在20世纪60年代走过来如此
that's even before my time as far as a
据 这连 我的时间之前 为
computer person but it's a very
电脑的人，但它是一个非常
important concept in the world of
在世界上 的重要概念
computers and then what they call the
电脑，然后他们叫什么
lower level stuff how it actually gets
低层次的东西它是如何实际获取
implemented is called the
实施被称为
microarchitecture
微架构
we will talk very very little about
我们会聊的很是很了解
microarchitecture in this course and as
微架构在此过程中 和
I mentioned machine code in sort of a
我有点提到过的机器代码
generic term that incorporates both the
通用术语， 既包括
actual bit the bytes that are operated
实际的位进行操作的字节
executing as well as the assembly level
执行以及汇编 级
version of it
它的版本
and as I mentioned you can think of from
正如我提到的，你能 想到从
instruction set point of view so ia32
的视图的指令集点，以便IA32
x86 64 and what's called Itanium or this
86 64，什么叫安腾或本
not very successful Intel thing those
不是很成功的英特尔 那些 事
are all in some ways different
都在不同的一些方法
instruction set architectures arm
指令集架构手臂
actually similar to Intel has gone
实际上类似于英特尔已经
through various different generations so
通过各种 不同的世代所以
there's various different generations of
有各种不同的代
its instruction sets so from a
其指令从设置等等
programmer machine level programmers
程序员机级的程序员
perspective things are a bit different
角度来看事情是有点 不同
than you see when you write C code first
比你看到当你第一次写C代码
of all there is some very visible parts
所有有一些非常显眼的部分
of the instruction the Machine State
指令机器状态的
that you can examine and test and
你可以检查 和测试
operate on and you must in fact that you
操作上，你必须在事实，你
would never understand what those are if
永远不会明白那些是什么，如果
you're just thinking in terms of C so in
你只是用 C 来 思考 这样的
particular there's some sort of a
特别是有某种类型 的
program counter to tells you what what
程序计数器来 告诉你什么什么
address is the instruction that you're
地址是你的指令
going to execute next where is that
下一步准备执行何方
located in memory and then there's a set
位于内存中，然后有一组
of registers which are part of the that
寄存器其是 的那 部分的
the programmer actually makes use of you
程序员实际上利用了你
can think of them as as a very small
可以把它们看成是一个非常小
number of memory locations but rather
的存储位置， 而是数量
than giving an address from 0 up to n
不是让一个从 0地址多达n
minus 1 or something you actually give
减去1或东西，你实际上给
them by name specifically and then
他们的名字特别，然后
there's another sort of state that's
还有另一种类型的状态这
just a few bits worth of state that
短短数位等值状态的那
talked about what what are the results
谈到什么是什么结果
of some recent instructions where they
最近的一些指令，他们
did it produce a value of 0 did it
没有它产生一个值 的0做到了
produce a negative or a positive value
产生负或正值
and those are used to implement
而那些被 用来实现
conditional branching which we'll look
条件分支，我们来看看
at later as we go and then the other
在 后来 ，因为我们去，然后其他
part of it so that sort of the processor
它的一部分，使得 排序处理器的
and then the other part of it is the
然后 它的 另一部分 是
memory and as I mentioned in the one of
存储器和如在我的所述一个提到
the first lectures the memory is you can
第一个演讲的内存，你可以
think of logically as just an array of
认为逻辑上只是一个数组
bytes and that's what the
字节，这是什么
machine level programmer C's and it's
机器级程序员C'S，它的
actually kind of a fiction in in
在实际类型的小说
different ways as I mentioned before
不同的方式正如我前面提到
they're sort of a collaboration between
这些人都 有点之间的合作
the operating system and the hardware
操作系统和硬件
what they call virtual memory to make it
他们称之为 虚拟内存 是什么 使它
look like each program running on a
看起来像一个正在运行的每个程序
processor has its own independent array
处理器有它自己的独立的 阵列
of bytes that it can access even though
的字节，它可以访问即使
they actually share values within the
他们实际上内 的 共享价值观
the physical memory itself and
物理内存本身
furthermore you heard the term cache the
此外，你听说过这个词缓存
idea of a cache is not visible here at
缓存的想法是 不可见的，在这里
all because it just is automatically
一切都是因为它仅仅是自动
loaded with recent stuff and the only
装载有最新内容，唯一的
thing that will look different is if you
这看起来不同的一点是，如果你
access that memory it will go faster
访问内存会走得更快
than it would if it hadn't been cached
比它，如果它 没有被缓存
but it's not visible in terms of there's
但它是不可见 的条款有
no instructions to manipulate the cache
无指示操纵缓存
there's no way you can directly access
有没有办法可以直接访问
the cache so you already see that it's
缓存 ，以便你已经看到它
already abstract it's got some more
已经抽象它有一些更多的
details of real Hardware but underneath
真正的硬件，但下面的细节
it that sort of microarchitecture level
它那种微架构的 水平
has some features built into it that
有一些功能内置到它那
you're not operating on you're not
你不是你操作不是
making use of direct way yeah when you
利用直接办法呀，当你
write machine level programs
写机水平的课程
so if you have a program then say and
所以，如果你有一个程序，然后说和
see it would typically on a larger
看到它通常会在更大
program that will include multiple files
计划，其中将包括多个文件
and it will make use of some library
它会利用一些库
code and so the process of compilation
码等编译的过程
is actually a series of steps that will
实际上是一系列的步骤，这将
take what you've written for code turn
采取什么样的你为代码编写的 转
it into machine code combine it with the
成机器代码 与它相结合
compiled compiler generated code for the
编译的编译器生成的代码的
libraries and produce finally a in a
库终于产生的
file that's your actual executable
文件的实际执行
program and svet shown here in this
程序和SVET在这所显示
picture that the first step is to take C
图像， 所述第一步骤是将Ç
and actually generate assembly code from
和实际产生从汇编代码
it and then the next is to run that
它再接下来是 运行
through an assembler which takes the
通过汇编它接受
text representation of instructions and
指令 文本表示 和
turns it into the actual byte level
把它变成实际的字节级
representation we'll look at all this
表示我们来看看 这 一切
shortly and then there's a program
不久，然后有一个程序
called a linker which merges together
称为 其 合并在一起 的接头
all the different files for both your
所有这两个不同的文件你
individual file their their compiled
单个文件的编译自己
versions and for the library code and
对于库代码版本和与
then finally there's a even once you run
后来终于有一个甚至一度运行
a program there's actually some
一个程序实际上有一些
libraries that get imported dynamically
是那些获得动态导入的库
when the program first begins so it's a
程序首先开始时，所以它是一个
sort of many layered set of activities
排序许多层次的一系列活动的
and I'll go through some of these
我会通过一些的这些
one-by-one for you so for example here's
一个接一个 给 你 因此， 例如 这里的
a not very interesting function in terms
在一个方面不是很有趣功能
of doing anything useful but it sort of
中做什么有用的，但它的排序
demonstrates two basic ideas of
展示的两个基本思路
compilation and if I run this through a
编译 如果 我通过运行这个
C compiler I get something that looks
C编译器我得到的东西看起来
like what's shown on the right and
像什么显示在右边，
that's the sembly code and just to give
这就是 sembly代码，并只 给
you an idea of what it is it looks like
你它是什么样子的想法
a sort of strange language the first
一种奇怪的语言第一
time you see it but you'll see those
一次 看到它 ，但你会看到那些
percent are something those are the
％的那些东西是在
actual names of registers remember I
寄存器的实际名称记住我
told you there's registers that you give
告诉你有，你给寄存器
by name and then those instructions are
按名称，然后将这些指令
telling it to do something push cue
告诉它做一些事情推 线索
means push something onto a stack
装置推东西到堆栈
move means move copy it from one place
此举意味着移动从一个地方复制
to another call means to call some
其他 呼叫意味着调用一些
procedure pop is the counterpart to push
程序的流行是 推动对口
and then rep is exit return out of this
然后代表是退出 回报出于此
particular function so you see each of
特定的功能 ，所以你看到 的 每一个
those is an instruction and it's written
这些是一个指令，它是写
in text but each of those will turn into
在文本，但每个那些 会变成
one actual instruction in the object
在对象的一个实际指令
code representation so I should tell you
码表示，所以我要告诉你
that this is actually a slightly cleaned
这其实是一个稍微清洗
up version of what really happens so let
起来到底发生了什么所以让版本
me show you the reality because you'll
我告诉你的 事实 ，因为你
be experiencing that a bit more - they
会遇到 多一点 -他们
had this bigger before let me make it
有这个大前请让我
bigger
大
and
和
pull this up so that you can see it set
这个拉起来，这样 你 可以看到它设置
can you see it in the back they're
你可以看到它在他们后面
bigger better
越大越好
and let me get the other one
让我得到了另外一个
in
在
and they've already logged into a fish
他们已经登录到鱼
machine to get here so this is a file
机器拿到这里，所以这是一个文件
then you see it's called some dot C and
那么你看这就是所谓的一些 点 C和
I'll mention that all of these programs
我会提到所有的 这些程序 是
are available you can see the whole well
可你能看到整个 井
slash AFS is my own personal and all
削减AFS是我个人和所有
that first stuff is my own personal
首先东西是我自己的个人
links but once you get to the class web
联系，但一旦你到 了类网页
page awwh code slash and then it's all
页面awwh代码斜线，然后这一切都
given by which particular lecture it is
由它是特别给定演讲
I think these are linked on the homepage
我觉得这些都是在 首页 链接
too and you can see various files there
太，你可以在那里看到各种文件
that are used for the demonstration the
这被用于示范
C files are obviously the programs that
C文件显然是程序，
we typed in and then one to have an S at
我们键入，然后一个有是S
the end that's assembly code one that Rd
这是汇编代码一个结束路
R what's called disassembly so anyways
[R什么叫做拆卸所以不管怎么说
if I say GCC - Bo - - Muslim sir - fo G
如果我说GCC - 博- -穆斯林先生- FO g ^
minus s capital some dot C that what I
减去资本 某些C点什么我
did was just tell the compiler to take
也只是 告诉编译器 接受
the C code and turn it into assembly
C代码并把它变成组件
code so when you invoke GCC you're
代码，这样，当你调用GCC你
actually invoking it's not just one
实际调用它不只是一个
program but a whole sequence of programs
计划，但节目的整个序列
that do various stages of the
该做的各个阶段
compilation and by giving it this minus
编译并给予它这个减
capital F switch I'm saying stop I'll
资本F开关我说停，我会
just do the first part C to assembly
只是做第一部分C到装配
code and the - Oh little G is a
代码和- 哦，小G是
specification of what kind of
什么样的规格
optimization I want the compiler to do
优化我希望编译器做
so if you don't say anything - just
所以，如果 你不说 什么 -只是
ignite
点燃
an optimized code and it's actually very
优化的代码，它其实很
hard to read that code it's very tedious
难以阅读 的代码是非常乏味的
the way it works if you say - oh one
如果你说的工作方式- 一个哦
which is what you used to do - turn on
这是你用来做什么的-打开
the optimizer it
优化它
turns out that as GCC as they've gotten
原来，由于海湾合作委员会，因为他们已经得到了
more advanced it does a lot of
更先进的 是做了很多的
optimizations now that for the purpose
现在的优化为目的
of this course make the code pretty hard
这当然使代码很辛苦
to understand so it just with one of the
了解所以 它 只是用的一个
most recent generations of GCC came out
最近的海湾合作委员会的代出来了
with this level called G for debugging
这个级别称为图G调试
that's a nice for this course purpose of
这是一个不错的的这门课程的目的
this course a nice level that it sort of
这门课程一个不错的水平，它的排序
does the obvious kind of optimizations
确实明显的一种优化
to make the code readable without being
使代码可读而不
sort of extravagant in trying to rewrite
那种奢侈的在试图改写
your whole program in a way that would
的方式，将您的整个程序
make it a lot different and hopefully
让很多不同，希望
more efficient so that's what we'll use
更高效所以这就是我们将使用
in this course it's only exists in the
在这个过程中它只有在存在
recent versions of the GCC it's
最近它的 GCC版本
non-standard across other compilers
在其他的编译器非标
question no it's an O capital o
问题没有它的O大写的 O
it stands for optimize so what that
它代表了优化，从而是什么
command just did was produce a file
命令只是没被产生的文件
called some dot F so let me show you
叫一些 点C以便让我告诉 你
what some dot s is and let me show you
什么一些点S是让我来告诉你
the function some store
该功能有些店
can you see that then okay
你可以看到，那么好吗
so this is the code it says some store
所以这是它的代码说，一些商店
and then you'll see you'll recognize
然后你会看到你会 认识
those instructions I mentioned before
我之前提到的这些指令
the push the move to call the must move
推动移动调用必须移动
the pop and the rest but you also see
弹出其余的 ，但 你也看到
other junk there that that we edited out
其他垃圾那里，我们编辑了
for the presentation and even in the
为演示文稿， 甚至在
book it got edited out and the reason is
书里得到了编辑出来，原因 是
these are various directives that aren't
这些是 不是 各种指令
really directly part of the code itself
代码本身 的真正直接一部分
the fact they start with a period is an
他们有一个周期开始，这是一
indication that these aren't actually
迹象表明，这些都不是真正
instructions there's something else and
说明还有别的东西
they all are related to what the
他们都涉及到什么
information that needs to be fed to a
需要被馈送到信息
debugger for it to be able to locate
调试器为它能够找到
various parts of the program and some
程序 和一些 各部位
information for the linker to tell it
链接器的信息告诉它
that this is a globally defined function
这是 一个全局定义函数
and various other things that you don't
而且，你不其他各种东西
really need to rethink about initially
真的需要重新思考最初约
so we sort of take those out of the
所以我们有点把这些出来的
program just to make them more readable
计划只是为了让他们 更具可读性
but if you ever do this yourself you'll
但如果你这样做 你自己，你会
find this crud in there and we don't
找到这个CRUD在那里，我们没有
want you to get like oh my gosh this
希望您能喜欢哦，我的天哪这
wasn't in the book I don't know what to
未在 本书中，我 不知道该怎么
do with it so let's go back
用它做让我们回去
the other thing is people are learning
另一件事是人 在学习
on data web is sharp versus non charkh
上的数据网络是 尖锐 对比非 charkh
it makes a difference and even like this
它的确与众不同，甚至这样的
is a Mac computer and I can rut got GCC
是Mac电脑，我可以得到车辙GCC
installed and it generates its Intel
安装和它产生了英特尔
processor in there but it's not directly
处理器在那里，但它直接不
compatible with Linux code so it's
与Linux的代码兼容，因此它的
pretty important for this course we're
这个过程中 ，我们是 非常重要的
saying just stick with the shark
他说只要坚持与鲨鱼
machines for everything you do so what
一切机器，你这样做是什么
are some characteristics that have
有一些 特性 有
assembly code especially how do they
汇编代码尤其是他们如何
differ from C well first of all there's
由C不同那么首先 有
a number of different sort of integer
许多不同的 排序整数 的
data types of size 1 2 4 and 8 bytes an
数据类型大小1 2 4 和8个字节的一个
integer data type they don't distinguish
它们不区分整数数据类型
sign versus unsigned in how it gets
注册与未签名的它是如何获得
stored and even an address or a pointer
储存和甚至地址或指针
is just stored as a number in a computer
只是存储为一个号码在计算机
and doesn't have any special
并 没有 任何特殊
significance to it a floating-point is
意义给它 的浮点是
handled in a very different way on the
在上一个非常不同的方式处理
other hand with a different set of
另一方面与一组不同的
registers that I think I'll talked about
注册了我想我会讲到
very briefly in one of the later
在后来的一个很简单
lectures the program itself is in x86
演讲的程序本身是在86
it's just a series of bytes and I'll
它只是一个字节串，以及我会
show you some examples of those and
告诉你这些的一些例子，
things like a raise and structs and
之类的东西 加薪和结构以及
things that you think of as fundamental
的事情，你觉得作为根本的
datatypes don't exist at the machine
数据类型 不会在机器上存在
level they're sort of constructed
水平有几分构建
artificially by the compiler and later
人为由编译器和后
in the course and these lectures will
在使用过程中和这些宣讲会
cross over into how that's actually done
跨 到怎么说实际上 已经完成了
as well so some of the things you're you
还有这样一些事情， 你是你
know about and see exists here and some
了解并看到 这里存在一些
of them are sort of have to be built up
他们都是那种 必须建立
in layers on top of the assembly level
在 装配水平的 顶层
program
程序
so the other thing about assembly level
所以有关 装配 水平的另一件事
programming is each instruction is very
编程是每一个指令是很
very limited in what it can do it can
在它能做什么非常有限它能
move data from a register to memory from
从寄存器 从将数据移动到 存储器
or it can do an addition or a
或者它可以做加法或
multiplication or something like that
乘法或类似 的东西
but it can really basically only do one
但是真正能够基本上只能 做一个
thing and and so you have to write a
的事情，所以你 必须写
whole if you were writing it by hand
整如果你手工编写它
you'd have to write a whole series of
你必须写一个全系列
instructions to get anything done and
说明做成任何事情和
that's part of the reason why it's
这是部分原因，为什么它的
really much better to what the compiler
真的好很多 的编译器是什么
do that and that will also see the sort
做到这一点，也将看到 排序
of how things like do loops while loops
之类的东西怎么办循环而循环
conditional switch statements those are
有条件的switch语句是那些
all built up on top of some other lower
所有建立在其他一些低顶
level features in the instructions so
在这样的指令级特性
for this function a some store actually
此功能 的一些商店居然
it gets encoded by a total of fourteen
它获得由总共 十四 编码
bytes and so one thing about x86 is some
字节， 这么一件事 约86是一些
instructions are as short as one byte
指令是短至一个字节
but others can be as long as 15 bytes
但也有的可能长达 15个字节
saw in the encoding and
在编码看到的和
Oh like I said each each instruction
哦，就像我说的每一个每一个 指令
really typically only does one thing so
真的一般仅做一件事情，所以
for example and see if you say star desc
例如，看看如果你说 明星递减
equals T what that will typically and
等于 吨 什么是通常会和
not always but this sort of way to think
不一定，但这种方式思考
about that at the machine level is it
有关机器 级是
ten years some local value would be
10年一些地方的价值将是
typically stored in a register and as
通常存储在寄存器中 并作为
you know and see if you put star in
你知道，看你把明星
front of it you want it referenced as a
它的面前 ，你想把 它当作一个参考
pointer and if that reference is on the
指针，如果该参考是 对
left you want to store a number of value
离开你想存储多个值
at that place where you're pointing to
在那里你指着那个地方
so what would typically happen is
那么什么会发生通常是
guessed that the actual pointer value
孰料实际 指针值
would also be stored in a register here
也将被保存在这里注册
it's in register RBX and i use a move
它在寄存器RBX我用一招
instruction to say take the value from
指示 说：要与值
one register which is called our ax here
一个寄存器，它在这里 呼吁 我们的斧头
and store it in the memory location
并将其存储在存储器中的位置
that's specified by another register so
多数民众赞成 由另一寄存器指定使
you see the idea we'll go into more
你看到的 想法 ，我们将进入更
detail about all these register names
所有这些寄存器名细节
and what the parentheses mean but you
什么括号的意思，但你
get the rough idea that a move
得到粗略的想法，一个举动
instruction is saying can refer to
指令是说可以参考
either a register or a memory location
任一寄存器 或存储器位置
and the actual object code
和实际的对象代码
representation of this is just three
这表示是短短三年
bytes where the first byte tells it that
字节，其中第一个字节告诉它
it and we would even talk much in this
它和我们甚至会在此说的多了
course about how the instructions are
当然有关 说明如何
encoded won't generally let programs do
编码一般不会让程序做
that for us but in this case it only
对于我们，但在这种情况下，只有
takes three bytes to write that
需要三个字节写
particular instruction so how can we
特定指令所以我们如何能
know that kind of stuff how can we
知道这种东西怎么样才
figure out that level of detail well
弄清楚详细程度以及
there's some really useful tools that
有一些真正 有用的工具，
let you examine machine code even if you
让您 检查机器代码 ， 即使 你
don't have a copy of the original C file
没有原来的C文件的副本
or even the assembly code file ahead of
甚至汇编代码文件提前
time and there's one called a
时间，有一个叫
disassembler so an assembler goes from
拆装所以汇编从去
this text version of instructions to a
这一指令文本版本的
byte level representation and the
字节级表示和所述
disassembler just reverses that it says
反汇编只是颠倒，它说，
here is a series of bytes
这里是一系列 字节
and I the disassembler know that this
我反汇编知道这
particular byte sequence refers is a
特定字节序列是指是一个
move instruction and so it will now
移动指令， 所以它现在将
print out on the screen to say oh that
打印出来的 屏幕 上说，哦那
was a move instruction and so it
是移动指令 ，所以它
basically reverse engineers from the
基本扭转工程师从
object code back to the assembly code or
对象代码返回到汇编 代码或
something sort of like the assembly code
东西有点像 汇编代码
you'll see it lost of what it's very
你会看到它失去 的是什么是非常
slightly different one thing also to
略有不同的一件事也
notice I should mention about assembly
注意到我应该提到关于议会
code is all those you know all the names
代码是你所知道所有 的名字
I used all the names of variables are
我用的所有变量的名称 是
completely lost at the assembly code
在汇编代码完全失去
level or the machine code level things
一级或 机器代码 级别 的东西
are just there in registers they're
只是没有在寄存器中他们
somewhere in memory the program has no
某处存储器中的程序有没有
understanding of your original source
原始源的理解
code at that level and so the
在 这一水平 ，因此代码
disassembled is just a way to go
拆解只是很长的路要走
backwards and you can do that yourself
向后，你可以做你自己
and you'll find that useful in various
你会发现各种有用
contexts and to do that yourself
背景和自己做
things kind of monkeying around music so
样的东西转转 乐这样瞎搞
if I compile the sum program
如果我编译 和程序
so if I do the more standard thing you
所以，如果我做你更标准的东西
do in using a compiler you say run the
在使用编译器做你说过的运行
compiler give it some optimization tell
编译器给它一些优化诉说
it what the source files are until where
它的源文件是什么，直到其中
to put the final executable code and I'm
把最后的可执行代码和我
terribly clever I call the function sum
非常聪明的我调用该函数总和
and so sum is a binary file of eight
所以总和为八的二进制文件
thousand six hundred sixty-three bikes
千663 自行车
you'll see off on the left it's marked
你会看到关上 它标志着左
as executable and it actually works I
如可执行文件 和它 的 实际 工作 我
can add numbers together with it so
可以用它一起添加号码，
that's the year the standard executable
这是这一年 的标准执行
program excuse me and if I run a program
程序原谅我，如果我运行一个程序
called object dump and ask it to
所谓的对象转储，并问
disassemble it can do various things it
拆开它可以做各种事情它
will spit out a disassembled version of
会吐出的反汇编版本
the program it will fly by on the screen
该计划将在屏幕上飞过
but if I redirect that to some file
但 如果我重定向 到一些文件
which I already did I'll remove the old
这我已经做我会删除旧的
one
一
and now I look at that you will see that
现在我看，你会看到，
it has what I described as is the
有什么样的我可谓是
disassembled representation of the
的拆卸表示
program including some files that you
程序包括一些文件， 您
didn't some functions that you didn't
这样做， 你没有不某些功能
write as ones that are sort of the
写成那些有几分的
low-level functions that are used in the
了在所使用的低级别的功能
initial startup of a program called in
一个叫做程序的初始启动
it
它
oops
哎呀
but here somewhere in the middle of it
但这里的某个地方在它 的中间
you'll see lo and behold is that program
你会看到你瞧是程序
that function some story that got
该 功能的一些故事， 得到了
compiled and you can see that what it
编译，你可以看到什么
did was it took this 14 bytes from the
确实是花 了 这14个字节从
original that the object code and it
原，所述目标代码和它
picked those apart and came back with
挑选那些开并 与之 回来
what instructions those bytes in code so
什么指令代码的字节，因此
for example the push instruction only
例如仅推送指令
takes a single byte the move as you saw
采用单个字节的举动，你看到的
before takes three bytes this call
之前有 三个字节 这个调用
because it has to give the location of
因为它给 的位置
where to call is a five byte instruction
其中调用是5个字节指令
and so forth but again the disassembler
等等，但 再次拆装
didn't have access to the source code it
没有访问源 代码，它
didn't have access even to the assembly
没有连 到组件 的访问
code it figured this out just by the
代码它由刚刚想通了这一点
bytes in the actual object code file so
在实际 的 目标代码文件字节，因此
this is the way if you ever want to know
这是方式，如果你想知道
actually the byte level encoding this is
实际上在字节级编码，这是
how you figure it out is to run a
如何你看着办吧是运行
program run it through an assembler get
程序通过一个汇编程序运行得
object code and then come back out with
对象代码，然后回来了与
it there's another way you can do it
它还有另外一种方式 ，你可以做到这一点
using the debugging program which you'll
使用调试程序，你会
get to know very well in the next web
了解得非常好，在未来网络
you're going to do and it's called gdb
你会做，这就是所谓的GDB
and gdb is a very powerful debugging
和gdb是一个非常强大的调试
program that you can examine step
程序可以检查的步骤
through and operate on programs in and
通过与在程序运行，
again you can if you if the source code
再次，你可以的，如果你如果源代码
for it's available it will make use of
它的可用 它 会利用
it but it also can be used on programs
它，但它也可以在程序 中 使用
for which there's no source available
对此有没有 可用的源
but one of the features is the ability
但的 特点 之一 是能力
to disassemble functions in there so if
拆卸功能，在那里，所以如果
I say disassemble some store
我说拆机一些商店
it'll come back with something that
它会回来的东西 ，
looks a lot like what you saw from the
看起来很像 你在看到了 什么
from object dump a listing of the
从对象转储的列表
instructions and here it just shows in
说明这里它只是 显示 在
hex what the addresses of those
十六进制这些东西的地址
different instructions are it doesn't
不同的指令它不
show the byte level encoding so there's
显示字节级编码，以便有
my point here is there's various tools
我的观点在这里 有各种工具
that let you look at a program even if
，让 你看即使程序
it's actual representation is a binary
它的实际表现 是一个二进制
file that you don't want to examine
文件，您不想检查
directly
直
I just plug this in
我只需将其插入这
so what this slide shows is what I just
还等什么这张幻灯片显示的是 什么，我只是
showed you on the screen which is what
显示 在屏幕 上 是 什么
the object dump program produces for
对象转储程序产生用于
this function and this is a version
这个功能，这是一个版本
showing what gdb would show you for it
展示什么GDB会告诉你吧
and with gdb if you want to actually get
并用gdb，如果你想真正得到
the bytes out you can do that you can
字节出来，你可以做到这一点，你可以
basically for any address you can just
基本上任何 地址你可以只
give an address and tell it to display
给一个地址 ， 并 告诉它显示
some number of bytes and so this rather
一些字节数等 ，而这
cryptic command to gdb says examine 14
神秘的命令GDB说检查 14
bytes in hex format starting at the
字节十六进制 格式起始于
address of the function sum store and it
功能和商店的地址，并将其
produced something that looks like what
生产的东西，看起来像什么
you see on the left
你看左边
in fact disassembly is a tool that can
其实拆卸是一个工具， 可以
be used as part of any of reverse
被用作任何 反向的 一部分
engineering tools and I used to demo
工程工具 和我用来演示
this by showing a disassembly of the
这通过显示的 拆卸
windows of Microsoft Word I had a PC
Microsoft Word中的窗口我有一台PC
back then not a mess but some people and
当时不是好惹的，但一些人，
you know our slides are online and so we
你知道我们的幻灯片是在线，所以我们
got some nasty grams from people saying
得到了一些人讨厌克 说
you know you're violating the Microsoft
你知道 你 违反了微软
end-user license agreement when you do
最终用户 许可协议，当你做
that because you're supposed to you
因为你应该给你
don't know this but remember all those
不知道这一点，但记得 那些
click through I agree things that you
通过点击我同意的事情，你
never read one of them is that we not to
从来没有读过其中之一是， 我们不
try to reverse-engineer any microsoft
尝试反向工程的任何微软
product so so this is when technically
这样的产品，所以这是 技术上时
so I'm sure just for modesty I blanked
所以我敢肯定，只是谦虚我空白
this out but you can actually do it if
这一点，但实际上你可以做，如果
you can find where the file is it's sort
你可以找到该文件是它的排序
of obscure where the actual executable
晦涩的地方 实际 的 可执行
files of an application now my point is
应用程序的文件现在 我的观点是
that words like any other application
那话 像任何其他应用程序
you run is just an executable file and
您运行只是一个可执行文件和
that executable file is just a bunch of
该可执行文件是只是一堆
bytes that encode instructions okay so
字节是编码的说明 好 了，
let's go a little bit further into this
让我们去一个远一点这个
to assembly level programming business
装配级编程业务
so I keep talking about registers and
所以我一直在谈论寄存器和
x86 64 has this totally quirky set of
86 64这是完全古怪的一套
registers and it's a reflection again of
寄存器和它 再次的 反映
this sort of evolutionary history to it
这种进化的历史给它的
but you'll see that there's 16 registers
但你会看到， 有 16个寄存器
that you can use to hold integers and
你可以用它来保持整数和
pointers and some of them have these
指针和他们中的一些有这些
sort of alphabetic names and some of
排序字母的名字和一些
them have numeric names I'll show you
他们有数字的名字，我会告诉你
why in a minute and also for each
为什么在一分钟，也是每个
register if you use the sort of percent
如果您使用的那种百分比注册
are name of it you'll get 64 bits but if
它是名字 ，你会得到64位，但如果
you use the percent II version of it
您使用的百分比II版吧
you'll get 32 bits and what you'll find
你会得到32位，你会发现什么
in programs that manipulate long in
在操纵在长节目
you'll see the use of are and if they're
你会看到使用的 是，如果他们
just in there
只是在那里
two-bit things you'll see code saying
二位 的东西，你会看到代码说
percent e so you'll see both of these
Ë 百分之 所以你会看到这两个
show up but and it's fairly important to
出现， 但它是公平重要
remember that the percent e version is
记住％的 E文版是
just the low order 32 bits of a larger
只是较大 的 低阶32位
percent our entity and in fact it goes
我们百分之实体，实际上它去
beyond that
除此之外
you can also reference the lower order
你也可以参考低阶
16 bits and the low order two bit I'm
16位和低位两位我
sorry one byte 16 want 2 bytes and one
对不起一个字节16要 2个字节 ，一个
byte within each of these registers as
内的每一个这些寄存器作为字节
well but again think of these as like
很好，但再想想这些像
named locations where you can store
命名地点，你可以存储
values and you can retrieve values from
值你 可以检索值
them and you have to you the suit of
他们和你有你的西装
personifying machine level programming
拟人机器语言
here not you personally will actually
这里不是你 个人 实际上会
have to explicitly name those registers
必须明确 命名这些寄存器
for the most part to say where things
大部分说那里的东西
should go where they should come out of
应该去的地方，他们应该出来的
it's not like a memory where you just
它不是你就像一个内存
give a number to tell where to look for
给一个号码告诉 到哪里寻找
you could compute a number there
你可以计算一个数值 存在
actually each one is identified
其实每一个被标识
separately so just as a little bit of
分别所以就像一点点
history with ia32 so back we just talked
历史与 IA32所以回到刚才我们谈到
about there being 8 registers all the %
大约有为8个寄存器的所有％
e versions and one of the changes that
Ë版本和变化一个
went from ia32 to x86 64 was to double
从IA32来到x86的64是翻番
the number of registers and by the way
寄存器的数量和方式
this is a really helpful thing because
这是一个非常有用的东西，因为
it was very frustrating how few
这是非常令人沮丧的多么少
registers there were in the old I 32
登记有在旧 我 32
machines and then the as I mentioned you
机器然后我提到你
could actually in the old machine refer
实际上可以在旧机器指
to the lower door 16 bytes of these
到下 门16个字节的这些
registers and that was a legacy from the
寄存器和这是从遗留
8086 days and within the first floor you
8086天和一楼之内 你
could even refer to the individual to
甚至可以参照个人
lord or bytes in those
主或 在这些 字节
so nowadays you can actually get to the
所以现在你可以真正得到的
low order byte of all of them and we
所有这些， 我们的低位字节
just sort of got that covered in the
只是有些得到了覆盖在
book actually we don't talk about how
本书实际上我们不谈谈 如何
you can get to these bytes because
你可以到这些字节，因为
that's really a legacy from back before
这是真正 从后之前遗留
the 8086 was one called the 8080 which
8086 一个叫 8080，其
was a an 8 byte machine so anyways you
是 一个8字节的计算机，以便反正你
can see then how you got from this kind
可以看到，那么 你是如何 从这种 有
of weird state of affairs to the even
事务的怪异状态， 偶数
weirder state that we are in today where
离奇的状态， 我们 在 今天的
some of them have names and some of them
其中一些人的名字 ，其中一些
have numbers and those names by the way
顺便说一下有数字和那些名字
had a reason back in ancient days they
有一个原因，早在远古时代 ，他们
had very specific purposes and so they
有非常 具体的目的 ，所以他们
were given names that sort of reflected
给予某种反映名称
those purposes but that that all went
这些目的但是，所有去
away years and years ago and so now
离开多年以前 ，因此现在
these names are just legacy names have
这些名字只是传统的名字有
nothing to do with their purpose now I
无关， 与他们的目的，现在我
should mention there's only there are
应该提到这里只有 有
some special there's one special
一些特殊的还有一个特殊的
register nowadays as shown in pink here
如图粉色 如今 这里 注册
and that's called the stack pointer and
而这就是所谓的 堆栈指针和
that register you don't just use any old
该寄存器你不只是使用任何旧
way you please it has a very specific
这样你请它有一个非常具体的
purpose and all the other registers
目的和所有其他寄存器
there's some that are slightly different
还有一些略有不同
than the other but for the most part
比其他的，但 在大多数 情况 下
they're all usable for holding program
他们都能够用于保持节目
data back in the ia32 days there was a
数据早在IA32天有一个
register called the base pointer that
寄存器称为基指针
also got used for procedures but that no
也 得到了使用程序，但没有
longer gets used anymore either
再得到 了 使用， 也可以
at least not usually so anyways I didn't
至少不是通常这样反正我没
want to I don't want to spend a lot of
想我不想花很多
time on historic legacy stuff and have
时间对历史遗产的东西，有
you memorized you know what feature was
你记住，你知道什么是功能
added and what model of processor but
添加和处理器的什么型号，但
just in case you're wondering why
以防万一你想知道为什么
there's these weird names for these
有这些这些奇怪的名字
things just so you appreciate the fact
事情只要你喜欢这样的事实
that this is a legacy thing
这是一个旧的东西
okay so now we can think of it then that
好了，所以现在我们可以把 它 想象 那么
there's eight registers with names and
有八个寄存器姓名和
there's eight registers that are
有八个寄存器是
indicated by some number and let's look
一些 数字 表明 ，让我们来看看
at some of the instructions that operate
在一些 该操作说明
on those registers and there's sort of
这些寄存器和有 几分
three different so move the move
三种不同的 移动使移动
instruction in x86 is actually can do a
在x86指令其实是可以做
lot of things because it can take
很多的东西 ，因为它可以采取
different types of information or what
不同类型的信息还是什么
they call operands so the source and
他们称这样的操作数源和
some where you're you're copying from
有些地方你是 你 抄袭
the source to the destination the source
源到目的地的源
can be some what's called immediate it's
可以通过一些什么所谓 即时它
actually a number that's baked into the
实际上那烤 成一个数
program that you want to copy into some
要复制 到一些程序
other location a register we've talked
其他位置 的注册，我们已经讨论过
about is one a specially named memory of
大约是一个特别命名的记忆
locations and memory is the array of
位置和存储器是阵列
bytes that you typically you have to
字节，你通常你必须
specify what's the address that you're
指定什么，你是 地址
either reading from if if it's the
无论是从，如果是，如果阅读
source are you writing to if it's the
源， 你写，如果它是
destination and so the move instruction
目的地等移动指令
gives you all these possibilities an
给你所有这些可能性的
immediate value can be written to a
立即值可以 被写入
register or directly to memory a
寄存器，或直接对存储器的
register value can be copied to another
寄存器值可以被复制到 另一
register or written to memory or you can
注册或写入到内存或即可
take a value from memory read it from
取的值 从存储器 读出它
memory and copy it to a register so if
内存并将其复制到寄存器，所以如果
you think of a wait shouldn't there be
你觉得等待的不应该有
nine different combinations here well no
这里九种不同的组合也没有
because it doesn't make sense to have an
因为它没有意义 的有
immediate value as a destination it's a
立即 值作为目标 这是一个
constant and also just for sort of the
常数，也只是排序的
sake of convenience so the hardware
方便起见所以硬件
designers it doesn't let you directly
设计师不会让你直接
copy from one memory location to another
复制从一个内存位置移到另一个位置
what you have to do is use two
你所要做的是使用两种
instructions one to copy from memory to
一个指令从内存中拷贝到
read it from memory
从内存中读取它
copy it to a register and a second to
将其复制到寄存器 和第二个
take that value in the register and
取该值 在 寄存器和
rewrite it to memory
它 改写 内存
so that's why there's this only five
所以这就是为什么有这个只有五
possibilities and so each of these
可能性和因此每个的这些
actual five combinations you'll see in
实际五个结合，你会看到
some form or another so for example if I
某种形式或另一所以，例如，如果我
take a constant value and copy it to a
取一个恒定值 ，并将其复制到
register it's a little like you can
注册它有点像，你可以
think of registries in sort of the
想登记 在排序 的
temporary data that you're operating on
临时数据，你的工作
right now so it's a way of sort of
现在所以它的排序的方式
assigning a constant value to a
分配一个恒定值的
temporary similarly if you're have a
临时同样，如果你有一个
memory as your destination it's like
存储作为目标，它像
storing a constant value in memory
在存储器中存储的恒定值
somewhere if you're copying from one
如果一个地方你从一个复制
register to another it's sort of like
注册到另一个它有点像
copying one temporary value to another
复制一个临时值到另一个
one register to memory it's as if you
一个寄存器 内存就好像你
it's sort of like storing to an address
它有点像存储到一个地址
so a pointer dereference where the
这样一个指针引用，其中
pointers on the left side the
左侧指针
dereference and memory to register is
解除引用和内存 寄存器是
the opposite it's your you're reading
相反它是 你的，你正在阅读
from some location into a temporary
从某个位置到临时
position so these Yosi all five versions
位置，以便这些 Yosi所有五个版本
get used in some form or another so now
在某种形式的习惯或其他所以现在
let's talk about how we write these
让我们来谈谈我们如何写这些
pointers how we specify either a source
指针我们如何指定一个源
or a destination for a memory reference
或用于存储器参考目的地
and you already saw one version of this
你已经看到了 这 一个版本
in fact in some of the code when you put
其实在 一些 当你把 代码
the name of a register in parenthesis
在括号中的寄存器的名字
that's just saying use this register
这只是说使用这个寄存器
whatever is in that that's an address
无论是在那一个地址
and use that address to reference some
并使用该地址引用一些
memory location and so you'll see
存储位置，所以你会 看到
something like this is equivalent of
这样的事情是等效
dereferencing a pointer and putting it
解引用指针，并把它
in there temporary
在那里 临时
you're also allowed to do a little bit
你也允许 做一点点
of arithmetic to derive an address from
算术的推导从地址
some collection of registers and other
寄存器 和其他的一些集合
constant values so if you see a number
常数值，所以如果你看到一个数字
called the displacement D in front of
称为 在前面的 位移 ð
this parenthesis it means to offset not
这圆括号就意味着不能抵消
use the address that's in the
使用这就是在地址
register but add or subtract some number
注册，但加上或减去一些数
from it to get an address that's just
从中得到，这只是一个地址
slightly off of it by some fixed amount
稍微偏离它由一些固定 量
and that we'll see is fairly useful for
而且我们可以看到是相当 有用
accessing different data structures so
访问不同的数据结构，从而
here is an example of a very simple
这里是一个非常 简单 的例子
function that we can understand
功能， 我们可以理解
everything about it already because we
关于它的一切已经因为 我们
know what the move instruction does and
知道移动指令做什么和
that the sort of classic swapping of two
此排序 的两款 经典 交换 的
values that are stored in memory so my
存储在 内存中 ，因此我的 价值观
point my arguments are two pointers
点我的论点是两个指针
called XP and YP and I'm going to
所谓的XP和YP 和我要去
dereference those pointers I'm going to
解引用这些指针我要去
read from memory into registers and then
从存储器读入寄存器，然后
I'm going to copy back to to memory but
我要去复制回内存，但
reversing the the two destinations and
扭转这两个目的地，
so as you can imagine it it lines up to
所以你可以想像它，它排队
be for move instructions that correspond
对于对应的移动指令
to these four references and the final
这四个参考，最终
one rekt just won't learn more about
一个rekt 就不会了解
functions and how they're called but
功能以及他们是如何调用，但
just think of the read is it gets you it
只是觉得读的是它可以让你它
returns from wherever the calling
从哪里调用返回
position was and so let's look at at
位置是所以让我们来看看在
more detail at the actual code then and
在实际的代码更详细然后和
so it turns out with 64 x86 64 the
因此，原来的64 86 64
arguments always come in some specific
参数总是在一些特定的
registers and the ones to remember for
寄存器和那些要 记住
today is Rd I will be the first argument
今天是我 路 将是第一个 参数
register and RS I will be the second
寄存器和RS我将是第二
argument register there can be up to six
参数寄存器 可以有 多达六个
of these and we'll go into more of that
这些和我们将进入更多的是
later so those two registers represent
后来所以这两个寄存器表示
the values of XP and YP those are set
XP和YP的值的设定
before when this before the function is
当此之前，该功能前
actually begins executing that's set by
实际开始执行多数民众赞成通过设置
the part of the code that calls this
该部分代码调用此
function and those will be pointers so
功能和那些会如此的指针
what they are is they contain addresses
它们是什么是它们包含地址
that specifying locations in memory
当指定在存储器位置
and then within the code the compiler
然后将代码编译器内
just came up with its own ideas of how
只是想出了自己的想法如何
to use different registers for temporary
用于临时不同的寄存器
data by whatever what's known as the
不论如何了所谓的数据
register allocation algorithm it uses
寄存器分配算法， 它使用
and we don't really care we just want
我们真的不关心我们只是想
what we'll want to do is figure out what
我们将要做的是弄清楚什么
it's doing and we'll see that a register
它在做什么，我们会看到一个寄存器
is our ax is being used to hold the
是我们的斧头被用来 举行
value T 0 and our DX of the value T 1
值T 0和我们的值T 1的DX
now so let's get actually concrete here
现在让我们开始实际具体位置
and this is very detailed but I think
这是非常详细的，但 我认为
it's important that you understand sort
这一点很重要，你 明白那种
of you can almost simulate the execution
你几乎可以模拟执行
of some instructions by yourself you're
通过自己的一些说明你
going to really have to know this stuff
要真的要 知道这东西
so what each of these instructions is
还等什么每一条指令是
doing and how it works and really have
这样做，它是如何工作的，并真的
that wired into you pretty well so let's
该接线到你很好所以让我们
make up an example I'll let's imagine
弥补了一个例子， 我会告诉我们想象
that the two addresses that are used for
这是 用于两个地址
these two pointers are in hex 1 2 0 and
这两个指针在十六进制1 2 0和
1 0 0 by the way those would not be
1 0 0顺便说那些不会
typical addresses they're way too small
他们来说太小了典型地址
a number but it's much easier to use
一个数字，但它更容易 使用
them as an illustration and let's
他们作为一个例证，让我们
suppose that one of them held the value
假设其中一人持有的价值
1 2 3 and the other 4 5 6 so the first
1 2 3和其他4 5 6因此第一
instruction says use RDI as an address
说明书上说使用RDI作为 地址
copy from that memory location and store
从该内存位置 和存储复制
the result and register R X so R di is 1
结果和寄存器 RX中以r di为 1
2 0 I'll read from that address I'll
2 0 我就从该地址读我会
read the value 1 2 3 and store it and
读出的值1 2 3，并将其存储和
register R ax these are all by the way 8
寄存器R 斧 这些都是由 8 方式
byte values and I'm just sort of
字节值，我有点刚
glossing over that part of it but the Q
粉饰它的一部分 ，但将 q
refers to what in Intel terminology is a
是指在英特尔术语是什么
quad word a word because it goes back to
四字一个字，因为 它可以追溯到
the 8086 is 16 bits 2 bytes a long word
8086是16位的2个字节 长的字
is 32 bits and a quad word is 64 bits
是32位，并且一个四字为64位
that
那
just their terminology and we're stuck
只是他们的术语和我们坚持
with it okay so that one instruction had
与它没关系 ，这样一个指令有
that effect the second instruction does
该效果的第二指令确实
the same thing but using RSI which holds
同样的事情，但使用RSI 持有
one zero zero as an address until it
一个零零 作为地址，直到它
copies four fifty four five six into RDX
副本四张五十四五六成RDX
and then the third instruction is
然后将第三指令 是
writing back to memory so it sources
写回内存， 因此 源
register RDX the destination has the
注册RDX 目的地有
address of r di which is one two zero
ř 二 的地址 是 一个两个零
and its storing that back in memory and
其存储，早在 记忆 和
finally the fourth instruction does the
最后第四指令做的
the other part of the right so you see
，所以你看到右边的另一部分
these four instructions to read from
这四个指令读取
memory into registers two of them wrote
内存到寄存器他们两个人写的
from registers back to memory and that's
从寄存器回内存，这就是
the whole function and you can see it
整体功能，你 可以看到它
this move instruction is is is doing all
这一举动指令时正在尽一切
the work here so we've shown that
这里的工作，所以我们已经表明，
example just showed this very simple
例如只是表明这很简单
memory referencing that's designated by
多数民众赞成由指定的内存引用
the parentheses and as I mentioned you
括号和我提到了你
can do a version where you put a
可以做你把一个版本
displacement there too and in fact
排量有 太多 而事实上
there's a much more elaborate form and
还有一个更复杂的形式和
we'll see that this is useful for
我们将看到，这是有益的
implementing array references where
执行数组引用哪里
there can be actually two registers
可以有实际上两个寄存器
involved and there can be a displacement
参与并且可以有位移
which is a constant offset and a scale
这是 一个恒定的偏移和比例
factor which will be one two four eight
这将是因素一二四八
and the general idea of it is to take
和它 的总体思路是走
our register that I'm referring to as R
我们的寄存器，我指的是为R
sub I that's known as an index register
这是有名的索引寄存器子我
you multiply it by the scale factor I'll
您可以通过比例因子 我将 它乘以
you add the value of RB register RB and
您添加RB 寄存器 的值 RB和
you also add the constant displacement
您还添加固定排水量
and these have a RB refers to base our
而这些有 RB指的是 我们的 基础
eye is index and s is scale and it turns
映入眼帘的是指数，s是规模，事实证明
out this will be the sort of natural way
走出这将是那种自然的 方式
to implement array reference it will
实施数组引用它 会
make a lot more sense when we talk about
使很多更有意义，当我们谈论
arrays
阵列
but basically you can think of is if
但基本上你能想到的是，如果
this is an array index I have to
这是一个数组索引 I必须
typically scale it by however many bytes
通常由然而， 许多字节它的规模
my data type is so if it's an entire to
我的数据类型是如此，如果它是一个完整的，以
scale it by four it's no long I have to
四缩放它 没有多久，我必须
scale it by eight so that's where these
八缩放因此，这就是这些
scale factors will come in and basically
规模因素将进来，基本上
the the format in the assembly code lets
在汇编代码的格式允许
you eliminate some of these fields if
你消除一些 领域如果
they're not being used so you'll and we
他们没有被使用 ，所以 你和我们
already saw that single parenthesis is
已经看到单一括号
sort of a reduced version of this form
排序的这种形式的简化版本
so let's just do some examples of these
所以 我们就做这一些例子
address computations and let's imagine
地址计算，让我们想象
that register RDX hold text F with three
该寄存器RDX保存文本˚F三
zeros and RCX held a one with two zeros
零和RCX举行了两个零一
so if I rather than doing one at a time
所以，如果我不是做一次一个
you can see each of these I'm taking RDX
你可以看到每 一个这些我正在 RDX
which is f with three zeros adding eight
这为f与三个零加入8
and so that's F zero zero eight here I'm
并且使公司的F 零点零八这里我
adding together registers RDX and RCX
相加寄存器RDX和RCX
and it gives me F 1 0 0 I'm doing the
它给了我f 1的0 0我正在做的
same here except that I'm scaling RCX by
同样在这里除了我缩放 RCX由
4 so 4 times 1 0 0 is is 4 0 0 and I'm
4，从而4次1 0 0是是4 0 0，我
adding that to F and here I'm taking RDX
并补充说，以F和我在这里取RDX
which is f 0 with 3 zeros if I double
这为f 0 与 3个零，如果 我的两倍
that I get 1e with 3 zeros if you think
我得到1E与 3个零，如果你认为
about shifting an F to the left 1 you
关于移一个F向左1你
get a 1 and then it goes 1 1 1 0 and
得到一个1，然后将它变为1 1 1 0
that's an e ok and then I'm adding this
这是确定一个e和我 加入这个
displacement of 8 0 to it so the point
的8 0位移到它，因此点
of this is all of this is arithmetic
这是这一切的是算术
it's all using whatever is in the
这一切都使用无论是在
register and there's some rules for how
注册并有 如何 的一些规则
you combine this and get an address and
你把这个 ，并得到一个地址 ，
then that's being used to either read or
那么系统会将此用来读取或
write some memory locations
写一些内存位置
okay so now what is the final part of it
好了，所以现在什么是 它的 最后一部分
today I'll go through some arithmetic
今天我会去通过一些 算法
and one of the things that we'll be sure
和的事情之一， 我们一定会
to confuse you and drive you crazy and
来迷惑你 ，推动 你疯了，
make you be sending email to the staff
让你可以发送电子邮件 给员工
for explanation is an instruction called
为解释是所谓的指令
load effective address and the reason is
加载有效地址和所述的原因是
its purpose in life is to do basically
其生活的目的是从根本上做
the ampersand operation of C to compute
C 的符号操作 ，以计算
an address based on some whatever you
基于一些地址随便你
want to compute an address from but it
要从但计算一个地址
also turns out to be a pretty handy way
也被证明是一个非常方便的方法
to do arithmetic and the C compiler
做算术和C编译器
likes to use it so in particular
喜欢在特定的使用它，
it looks the the format of it looks like
它的外观格式 ，它看起来像
a move instruction there's a source and
移动指令有 一个源
a destination but the destination has to
一个目的地，但目标 必须
be a register and the source will be one
是寄存器和源极将是一个
of these memory references so it looks
这些内存引用，因此它看起来
like a move instruction it looks like
就像一个移动指令，它看起来像
you're doing some address computation
你正在做一些地址计算
then you're reading from memory and
那么你从 内存中 读取 和
storing it to a register but what it
它存储到寄存器，但它是什么
actually does is it does that address
实际上做的是它那个地址
computation and then it actually writes
计算，然后它 实际上写
that address not the memory value but
该地址无法在存储值，但
the the value of got that got computed
这得到了计算GOT的价值
directly to the register which is what
直接向这正是寄存器
you want to do here remember the
你想在这里做记得
ampersand operation is give me the
符号操作是给我
address of some place give me a pointer
一些地方的地址给我一个指针
that designates some location so for
， 指定一些位置，所以对于
example this is fairly typical in C code
例如， 这 是 在 C代码 相当典型
if you say multiply X by 12 it will turn
如果通过12多次说这 X 会变成
it into a le Lotus and address
它为乐莲花和地址
computation and this is just a clever
计算而这仅仅是一个聪明的
way to compute three times our GI adds
一种计算 三倍我们的GI增加
are di plus two times r di so that three
是二加二次数R迪这样三个
times R di and stores it in our ax and
次数R迪并将其存储在我们的斧头和
then Sal Q means shift left by two and
然后萨尔Q表示由 两个和 左移
so you remember shifting up by two is
所以你还记得由两个上移是
like multiplying by four so the first
像由 四个，第一 乘以
value computed three times X I shift
值计算三次XI移
that left four by two positions and I
由两个位置，我留了四个
have twelve times X so that's a very
有十二倍X所以 这是一个非常
special that le.a but you'll see it all
特别 是le.a但你都看到它
over the place so you need to be ready
的地方 ，所以 你需要做好准备
for it these other ones look more like
它 这些其他的看起来更像
what you'd expect for arithmetic
你所期待的算术
instructions they have names like add
说明 他们有 像添加 名称
and subtract and multiply and so forth
和减法和乘法 等等
and they all have the same general
它们都具有 相同的一般
format that they have two arguments and
他们有两个参数的格式和
what's called the destination is
什么所谓的目的地是
actually also a source it's a little
居然还源这是一个有点
like in C if you say X plus equals Y
像在 C，如果你说X 加等于 ÿ
it's saying take the value of x add the
它说需要 x 的值 加
value of y and then store the result in
的Y值，然后将结果存储在
X and now the destination is like that
X现在的目标就是这样
the other thing that's weird is that the
这是奇怪的另一件事是，
operands are in the inverse order from
操作数是在从逆顺序
where you'd expect them to be so the
在你期望他们是这样
source comes first in the destination
源至上在目的地
comes last and that's important to
排在最后，这就是重要
remember
记得
and other thing you'll see that there's
和其他的事情，你会看到有
nothing special here whether it's a
这里没有什么特别它是否是一个
except that this is a arithmetic shift
不同之处在于这是 一个算术移位
and this is a logical shift of whether
这就是是否逻辑移位
it's assigned your unsigned value
它赋予 你的无符号值
because you remember the bit level
因为你还记得位水平
behavior of these two instructions is
这 两个 指令 的行为 是
the same and then there's a series of
同样的，然后有一系列
instructions that are used that are just
即使用该指令是刚
take one operand increment decrement a
只有一个操作数递增递减一
negate and not not is not is like the
否定而不是不是不是就像
tilde operation and see not the
波浪操作，而不是看到
exclamation mark so those are the basic
感叹号所以这些都是基本
instructions and again now we can
指令和再现在我们可以
actually look at some programs and
其实看一些节目和
understand them and here's one that just
了解他们， 这里有一个刚
does a bunch of junk of arithmetic
做了一堆算术垃圾
instructions and it converts into the
说明，并将其转换成
following assembly code and you see it's
下面的汇编代码，你会看到它的
using this LA instruction multiple times
使用此 指令LA 多次
to do addition in various forms and it
做加法各种形式和它
also has shifting and it has
也有移并且它具有
multiplication you saw in the original
乘法你在原来看到的
code I just have addition and
代码我只是添加 和
multiplication here I have various
乘我在这里有各种各样的
instructions I only have one multiply
说明我只有一个 乘法
here whereas I had two there so the
在这里，而我有两个有这样
compiler instead of scrambling things
编译器，而不是扰乱的事情
around trying to find clever ways to
周围试图找到巧妙的方法来
implement what you're asking for using
实现你问使用
less complex expensive less
更简单更便宜
time-consuming instructions
耗时指示
and if you sort of go through this code
如果你就想通过这个 代码
carefully what you'll find is that this
小心你会 发现， 这
instruction here corresponds to this
这里指令对应于此
computation of t1 is adding two values
T1的计算是将两个值
and giving it a new name it's putting in
并给它它把新名称
our ax similarly this one is adding V to
我们的斧头同样这一项加V至
t1 and storing it back in in our a X the
t1和我们在一个存储回X的
x box for doesn't show up directly here
对于x框显示不出来 直接在这里
it turns out what it does is it jumps
事实证明，它的作用是它跳到
right it head to here and multiply Y by
正确的 IT 前往 这里繁衍Y上
48 it does it by first computing 3y like
48它通过它第一计算3Y等
we saw before and computing shifting
我们以前看到和计算转移
that left by 4 because 3 times 16 is 48
留下由4，因为3次 16 48是
and then the 4 here that sin x plus 4
然后4这里罪x 加4
actually shows up here it just uses the
这里实际显示了它只是使用了
displacement field of this computation
这种计算位移场
to add 4 to some other values and so
添加4到一些其他的值等
this is labeled then these comments show
这个标记，那么 这些言论表明
how these correspond to the program and
如何将这些对应的程序和
these registers show it so the important
这些寄存器显示它如此重要
thing to get from here you will want to
事情得到 从这里 ， 你 会想
actually go back through this and make
其实回去通过此，使
sure you believe that the comments are
一定要相信，评论是
correct but it's very important for you
正确的，但它是非常重要的，你
to figure out this la instruction
要弄清楚这个 LA指令
otherwise you're just going to be
否则你只是要
hopelessly confused
绝望的困惑
and it's also important to understand
而且同样重要的是理解
that the the code that gets generated
该获取 生成的代码
will correctly implement your si
将正确地贯彻执行贵驷
function but it might not exactly
功能但它可能不完全
replicate at a low level
复制处于较低水平
the exact sequence of operations you
操作的确切顺序你
specified at a high level so that will
在较高的水平， 这样 将会在指定的
just to summarize then you've already
只是总结，那么你已经
gotten a glimpse then of of what this
得到的一瞥，然后的这是什么
very odd world of machine programming is
机器编程的非常奇怪的世界
and how different it is from C code
以及如何不同它是从C代码
already it's also you've already seen
是的，还是你也已经看到了
that x86 is weird like I said it's
这是x86的怪异就像我 说的
English it's not a Latin it's not well
英语这不是一个拉丁这不是很好
designed and but you just got to deal
设计，但你刚处理
with that so that's your beginning to
与 让 你的开始
machine level programming thanks a lot
机器语言非常感谢
I
一世